MUSKAN SOOD

(DATA ANALYST/QA ANALYST)

Ph: +91-999-194-0506

Email: sood.muskan@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Adaptable Data Analyst and QA Analyst skilled in recording, interpreting, analysing and verifying data in a fast-paced environment using latest technology of data science. Advanced proficiency in all aspects of Excel. Experienced in preparing detailed documents and reports while managing complex internal and external data analysis responsibilities.

EDUCATION

Course	Specialization	Education board/University	Percentage	Year of Completion
Bachelor of Technology	Computer Science	Kurukshetra University	71.5%	2014
Senior Secondary	Science	CBSE Board	73%	2010
High School	NA	CBSE Board	77%	2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company	Designation	Duration
Tata Consultancy Services	System Engineer	January 2015 - March 2018
Infosys	IT Analyst	April 2018 – June 2018
IBM	System Specialist	July 2018 – Present

ROLES

ETL Tester/QA Analyst

- Sole owner of performing testing life cycle of a module
- Extensively worked with flat files, excel sheet & database
- Developed SQL queries for complex mapping with 200+ LOC
- Performed System, Integration and User Acceptance Testing
- Performed Automation and Compatibility Testing using scripting language
- Developed high level test matrix based on business requirement
- Expertise in RDS and Data warehousing concepts

Data Analyst

- Attain full understanding of Business requirement
- Responsible for preparing around 50 of Business Objective Reports
- Extracted meaning full information from structured and unstructured data using SQL

- Expertise in all aspects of Excel to represent the reports
- Used IBM in-built reporting tool for data mining and reporting

Team Lead

- Supervised team of 12 members
- Delivered 10 short term project modules and 2 major complex modules on time
- Trained team members so that they can learn and grow
- Held stand up calls and scrum meetings to ensure the proper coordination among the team members

SKILL SET

Programming Languages	C++, Java, Phyton, VBScript	
Query Languages	SQL	
Tools used	Oracle, SQL Developer 4.0.2, UFT, JMeter, Teradata, SQL Assistant 14.01,	
	DB visualizer, Tableau	
Test management Tool	HP Quality Center v.10.0, ALM 11	
Editing Tools	MS-Word, MS-PowerPoint, MS-Excel, MS-Access	

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2018: Felicitated with FSS award in IBM
- 2017: ISTQB Advance Certified, TCS Star of the month Award
- 2016: TCS On the Spot Award, Multiple Client Appreciation Award for Timely and Quality Delivery
- 2015: TCS On the Spot Award, FTC certification in Insurance Domain

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY HELD

- November 2017 Present: Team Lead
- 2016: Event Organiser for TCS and President at Fun at Work
- 2015: Stage coordinator and Anchor in number of events held in ILP, TCS
- 2012: Student Coordinator for CSE department, JCDMCOE
- 2009: Head Girl at Secondary School, The Sirsa School
- 2007: House Prefect at High School, The Sirsa School

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Travelling
- Trekking
- Reading
- Cooking